<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Bill Ochieng</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Bill Ochieng</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 08:10:29 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Brief introduction to my current interests</title>
      <link>/posts/currentinterests/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 08:10:29 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/currentinterests/</guid>
      <description>My current research interest is app development with Xcode, Swift &amp;amp; SwiftUI. SwiftUI is Swifts graphical counter part, and is responsible for the graphics behind an iOS or MacOS app. It caught my attention as I like the idea of being able to create solutions for issues or inconveniences in mine, and others day to day life with their smartphones and computers. I also love how Xcode incorporates an emulator to preview each line of code as you right it in real time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java</title>
      <link>/skills/my-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 08:10:29 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/skills/my-project/</guid>
      <description>I have been working with the Java language since Highschool on and off. It is one of my favorite languages to work with and one of the most popular out there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python</title>
      <link>/skills/python-info/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 08:10:29 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/skills/python-info/</guid>
      <description>Python is my favorite language I have learned, and the one I am most comfortable working with! I love its simple and elegant design. It is easy to pick up and quick to write. I have been working with python for the past 3 years now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SQL</title>
      <link>/skills/sql-info/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 08:10:29 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/skills/sql-info/</guid>
      <description>I am not as experienced in SQL as I am Python or Java, however I have taken a course that revolved around queries and SQLITE databases and was very interested in the language.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Swift (In Progress)</title>
      <link>/skills/swift-info/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 08:10:29 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/skills/swift-info/</guid>
      <description>Swift is the next language that I am currently learning. It&amp;rsquo;s use for creating iOS apps and software sparked my interest. I have begun learning this language however it is marked as in progress as I am not at a proficient level with the language yet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tic-Tac-Toe made with PySimpleGUI</title>
      <link>/projects/my-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 08:10:29 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/my-project/</guid>
      <description>About the project You can find the current release on Tic-Tac-Toe!
This was a final project for my software engineering class, and was quite a challenging one. It was my first time implementing graphics into a Python program. This was done using PySimpleGUI which was a challenge in it self to learn, however well worth it. Over all the project was fun to complete, and gave the user a nice looking way to play tic-tac-toe against friends or an AI.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
